MICHAEL C. DILUCCA

dilucca.dev • nuka.dilucca@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/michaeldilucca

GAMEPLAY ENGINEER

► Linking teams and technology to create memorable player experiences ◀

Diligent, proactive, and versatile *Gameplay Engineer* offering strong technical expertise, efficient solutions, and the capacity to understand changing industry methodologies. Able to see the forest and the trees, connect the dots, and effectively manage competing priorities in time-sensitive environments. Self-confident and collaborative developer who treats all team members with respect and earns the same in return. Consistently drive projects across the goal line and exceed expectations using active listening, quick study, consensus building, and a determined belief in always finding a way.

APPLIED SKILLS & KNOWLEDGE

- System Design
- Software Development
- Game Development
- Agile Scrum Methodology
- Extreme Ownership

- User Interface Architect
- Strong Communication
- Software Testing
- User Experience Design
- Data Research & Analysis
- Code-Standard Compliance
- 3D Math / Physics
- Time Management
- Team-Oriented

Technical Proficiencies

C# - C++ - Java - Python

Unity • Unreal Engine • Adobe Creative Cloud

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Aтом Swiтch, Inc. - Remote ■ 2023 - Present

Senior Gameplay Engineer

Tied systems together as a flexible developer working alongside programmers and designers and at times playing the roles of both. Planned and incorporated systems, ground up from design documentation to final test. Worked in fluid and ever-changing project management methodologies to find what worked best given the specific deliverable, timeline, and team size.

INFESTSTATION

- Outlined and designed initial game AI systems that were later incorporated into an experience director.
- Developed a Mission System framework from the ground up to work in tandem with procedurally generated maps.
- Jointly incorporated audio systems alongside audio director.
- Organized community playtesting groups, gathered feedback, and presented data to the team.
- Implemented pre/post-game multiplayer lobbies using Online Subsystem.
- Released INFESTSTATION on <u>Steam</u> in 2024 on UE 5.3 with Nanite and Lumen technologies.

FLIGHT SCHOOL STUDIO - Remote • 2020 - 2023

Interactive Developer

Fortified unique skill sets while working in a multifaceted position in a stimulating and evolving environment. Designed diverse and scalable projects of myriad sizes for installations around the US while working in close-knit and efficient teams.

Glow Tennis (American Express)

- Develop a system that used HTC trackers and base stations to track user velocity and acceleration.
- Program a full pong game with intuitive items following ever-changing requirements based on bi-weekly client feedback.
- Provided live support at the 2022 US Open with swift bug fixes, seamless deployment via teamviewer.

Krazy Kart (AT&T)

- Crazy Taxi meets SSX Tricky at Pebble Beach for a golf cart installation featuring Jordan Speith.
- Programmed character controller and leaderboard side application.
- Integrated input system to support multiple platforms.

RUMBLE Match

- A mobile match 3 game released simultaneously with the WWE animated film, Rumble.
- Programmed comic book features that are used to add a fun and intuitive story element to the game between levels.
- Add analytics, online store, and ad services.

THE BOEING COMPANY - Ridley Park, PA • 2016 - 2020

Senior XR Developer

Built team of 15 developers from the ground up operating in a start-up mode to identify, develop, test, and apply new technologies for a variety of business applications. Interfaced with key stakeholders including executive management, military generals, and astronauts to secure project funding. Traveled across the US to interact directly with customers to understand and negotiate project details, budget, and terms. Served as lead developer and a founder of the XR Center of Excellence (XRCoE).

Discovery Ocean (DISCOVERY Education)

- Created a virtual experience for Oculus products to introduce users to the Echo Voyager, a Boeing UUV (Unmanned Underwater Vehicle).
- Developed application for users to learn about marine life, the environmental issues impacting the oceans and the actions Boeing is taking to advance marine technology.

Discovery Mars (DISCOVERY Education)

- Designed the system architecture and storyboard of the game through an iterative process with the customer and stakeholder.
- Originated a Martian virtual environment for the user to learn about Mars and the requirements for humanity to survive on the planet through a series of multiple experiences including:
 - Rover repair, allowing the user to attach replacement parts to the curiosity rover, where every part placed educates the user on its functional use, and upon completion, provides the opportunity to interact with a console to program the rover on a grid-based mission.
 - Growing a plant in a lab where the user must filter soil from the Martian surface and genetically modify seeds to ensure the best chance for survival.

SHADOW CIRCUIT (DREXEL UNIVERSITY) - Philadelphia, PA • 2016 – 2017

Project Lead

Directed team of 12 developers for senior design project to create a VR futuristic handball game using Unreal Engine 4.

- Designed unique game mechanics with C++ as an integral part of the central game loop (Gravity Wells, Gravity Whip, Goal Looping); programmed multiple game aspects (AI, Scoring, Platform Mechanics, and Main Menu Interaction).
- Released Shadow Circuit to <u>Steam</u> in March 2017.
- Awarded Drexel University's "Best VR Experience" by both the College of Computing & Informatics and the Antoinette Westphal College of Media Arts & Design.
- Received Distinguished Engineering Project Achievement Award.

EDUCATION